So, you hail from the same school as a
couple other great Dolphins linebackers,
one current in Jordan Brooks, another
one a Hall of Famer, Zack Thomas. Uh,
what does it mean to you to potentially
be next?
>> It means a lot to me. I think, um, you
know, Jordan has has given me a lot of
words of wisdom, you know, as I've gone
through my years here and then, you
know, I was able to create a good
relationship with, you know, Zach Thomas
and he's been a mentor to me and he's,
you know, let me reach out to him for
any questions I have. And um it's just
it's been a it's a really cool
experience to be in this position to
have, you know, guys who were in your
same spot and now you know they're
they're leaning into this experience
just like you are right now.
>> Excellent. I appreciate that. Welcome.
>> Thank you.
>> Isaiah,
>> what's going on? Jaya Smalls from the
Miami Herald. How are you?
Congratulations.
>> I'm great. Thank you.
Uh, so my one of my favorite games for
me was I believe that two pick
performance that you had in the Big 12
title game against BYU. Um, I know
you're a former quarterback, so I'm
curious how did you how did that
experience kind of affect the way that
you cover?
>> Um, that that game it was I didn't have
two picks that game, but um, I I uh I
feel like I could cover well. I think it
helps with uh you know playing
linebacker or playing quarterback and um
you know being able to see the field a
different way but um yeah that that one
that was my uh other that was my
teammate.
>> My apologies.
>> No, it's all good.
>> Joe,
>> hey Jacob, it's Joe with Palm Beach.
Nice to meet you.
>> Nice to meet you.
>> Obviously Zach Thomas is
>> uh greatly admired in these parts. um
what's one thing that he has, you know,
said to you that you can share that's
been helpful?
>> He's just kind of, you know, reminded me
of um kind of what he went through and
this process that he kind of went
through and, you know, how he had to,
you know, believe in himself and um just
kind of hold true to, you know, what
he's had and and you know, kind of what
he's earned and, you know, you got to
especially being from West Texas, you
know, you got to you work hard every day
and that's kind of got to be your
routine. And so, um, you know, just
feeding into a lot of the day-to-day
stuff and and, um, a lot of that we kind
of elaborated on.
>> How do you get so many turnovers?
>> Uh, I think I have great teammates who
are able to be there to pick the ball up
if I'm able to punch it out or leave
pressure on the quarterback when I'm
able to, you know, pick the ball off
through the air.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you,
>> Jose.
>> Congratulations, Jacob. Um, I wanted to
ask you, how much do you embrace the
opportunity to represent the Hispanic
community in the NFL?
>> I think it means a lot to me. It's, um,
it's a tremendous experience. I think,
uh, you know, with with my family and
everything that, um, you know, we
believe in and who we are, uh, it's a
big deal and, uh, we take that seriously
and I'm ready to be to be down there and
get involved in the community and be a
part.
>> Marcel,
>> hey, Jacob. Marcel Jacqu with ESPN.
Welcome to Miami and congratulations
first of all Arizona State fan so I'm
happy not to have to watch you play
against them anymore but uh I know
you're a converted quarterback. Can you
run us through the process of I guess
how the decision was made that you would
no longer be a quarterback and how you
were steered to playing linebacker?
>> Yeah. Well, ASU got the best of us this
year, so I guess I'm happy. But, uh,
yeah, and the the transition started,
um, you know, after my freshman year, my
head coach decided to step down and, uh,
so I ended up in the transfer portal
because he was no longer going to be
there. You know, I wanted to play for
him. And then, uh, Coach Magcguire just
got the job at Texas Tech and he had
offered me as a a scholarship player at
Baylor when he was there as a
linebacker, even though I didn't play in
high school. And so when he got the job
at Texas Tech, you know, I reached out
and my head coach from high school
reached out to him and I had some
buddies who went there out of high
school and played for him. And so, uh,
it was kind of easy transition, but it
was more so, you know, as soon as I got
there, it was understood that I was
going to move positions and, you know,
he didn't have any scholarships left.
So, I knew that coming in that I was
going to have to, you know, be a
linebacker and be a walk-on. Um, but
then again, you know, it got so close to
before school started where, you know, I
got to go to school somewhere. I can't
just, you know, not start the semester.
So, uh, you know, I ended up, you know,
believing in him and and, you know,
trusting in his word that he gave me
and, um, I think it's worked out pretty
good so far.
>> I would say so, too. If I could follow
up real quick, how long did it take
before you felt really comfortable in
that role on the other side of the line
of scrimmage?
>> Yeah, it took about a year, I think. Um,
you know, at first you're really just
trying to understand how to play
coverage and how to play defense in
general. And a lot of it started with
just middle closed run to the you know
play your gap and then run to the ball.
Play your gap and then run to the ball.
There was never really any overlap or
any playing within the scheme of the
defense. And and so it took me about a
year to finally understand scheme and
you know with my back to coverage now
how to play in and around with people
and how to communicate well because as a
quarterback you're just kind of barking
out everything that everybody has to do.
Well now you're you're barking it out
but then you also have to listen to
other people and you know communicate
that way. So that's what I would say
about a year and then uh you know I
think it took off from there.
Got it. Appreciate it, man. Congrats,
sir.
>> Thank you.
>> Hal.
>> Hi, Jacob. Hell havoc with the Palm
Beach Post. Welcome to South Florida.
>> Thank you. Thank you.
>> Um, when you hear something like Zack
Thomas, Hall of Famer, saying that Jacob
Rodriguez is the best defender we've had
at Texas Tech. How do you process
something like that?
>> Uh, you don't. I think um that's
something that really has just you know
stood out and uh it's hard to believe
and uh you know I I take his word very
seriously and I appreciate who he is and
everything he's done and uh the mentor
and the man he's been you know to me and
to my family and um yeah it's
unbelievable. It's super generous and
super kind from him and that just kind
of shows you how great of a person he is
and why he's so admired in Texas Tech as
well as in Miami.
>> If I could uh change gears real quick
before I let you run to the next
questioner. Um, I'd like to get uh your
thoughts on how proud you must be of
your wife and what you could tell us
about where she might be in the world
right now.
>> Yeah. Yeah. My wife is uh, you know, a
huge counterpart to me and then, you
know, she she keeps me on the straight
and narrow in everything I do. And so,
she's actually fortunate enough to be
here tonight. So, she's here with me and
um, the whole family's out here. So,
it's uh she means a lot to me in
everything that she does in her
professional life, but most of how much
she's is able to support me and, you
know, hold me help me through this
entire process.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you,
>> Chris.
>> Hey, Jacob. Chris Perkins, South Florida
Sun Sentinel. Congratulations.
>> Thank you, sir.
>> Hey, uh you do so many things well.
You're a three-own player. You make
tackles, sacks, force fumbles,
interceptions. How do you measure your
value to a team?
>> I think u you know my I think my value
is a lot of it has to do with you know
being the position that my coaches put
me in and I think they they put a lot on
my plate and a lot of it you know I was
either asking for or you know I was I
was ready to take on that challenge. And
so I was just really appreciative of
them to put me in all those spots to you
know get everybody lined up and and make
them do what they do. You know we had a
lot of great teammates this year and so
it was fun for me just to be able to set
them up for success. And you know, if we
get those guys going and playing hard,
then you know, all I have to do is just
do my job. And so, uh, it means a lot. I
think I'm a very versatile player. I
think I can play kind of all around the
field and do whatever the the team needs
of me and what's whatever is asked of
me. And so, I think that's kind of where
I can add value.
>> And as a quick followup, what do you
consider a successful game? Let's take
wins and losses out of it because I know
you you might say if we win, it's a
successful game. Are are there stats?
Are there other things, intangibles that
that factor into what you would consider
a successful game for you?
>> Um, I mean, I think when you're playing
a team game, you can't really take wins
and losses out of it. I think, uh, you
know, it's a whole collective. You could
play a perfect game and still lose. And
so, that's why I think, um, you know,
success is measured by, you know, wins
and losses. I think you can you can
learn a lot from failing. You can learn
a lot from losing, but the ultimate, you
know, goal of the game is to to be there
for for the one and0 at the end of the
week. Right.
Thanks.
>> Thank you,
>> Omar.
>> Um, Jacob, I'm curious. Do you speak
Spanish? Number one.
>> No, I don't.
>> Okay. And you said, especially being
from West Texas, what's West Texas like?
>> Uh, West Texas is uh it's full of
amazing people and it's tough and it's
gritty. And I think um being from around
there and and you know getting to know
that whole entire community, I think uh
everybody from around there is
hardworking and they do whatever it
takes to provide and then feed for their
family. And um it's something that you
know we kind of took over this year is a
team out there in love is you know
everybody kind of comes from all around
West Texas. You know we're we're the
only school the only you know pro team
you know within five six hours. And so,
um, you know, everybody comes out to
support us. And so, if they're they're
paying, they're using their hard-earned
dollars to come see us play. That's kind
of what we need to do to repay them is
is just put as much in of the hard work
and the dedication that they do to their
families every single day.
>> Um, and and if I may follow up with that
question with the question about your
your wife, I know she she pilots
helicopters. Where is she like stationed
in the world normally? I know she's
there with you now, but um I guess you
guys live apart.
>> Yes, sir. Yeah, we've been doing long
distance and uh she she's stationed in
Fort Riley, Kansas right now.
>> Okay.
Thank you.
>> Yes, sir. Thank you,
>> David.
>> Hey, Jacob. David Fus of the South
Florida Sun Sentinel. Again, uh I know
leadership is a big part of what you
provide to a team. How do you manage
that as you're about to embark on being
a rookie on a professional team? Uh, and
maybe when do you kind of figure you
start to take on a leadership role in
the NFL?
>> Yeah, I think um it starts with just
being consistent. I think coming in and
being the same guy every day. And I'm a
big believer in knowing your role and
whatever that is, you know, trusting in
that and and believing in that, but
always trying to improve it. And so, you
know, the best teammate I can be is what
I can be. And uh no matter if you're a
rookie or you're, you know, a 15-year
vet, you know, you got to have a certain
command and certain confidence value to,
you know, move around the facility and
move around on the playing field. But a
lot of it comes down to just the
relationships that you build with the
people who you're around and and the the
dedication to them and and to the people
who they care about.
>> All right. Thank you.
>> Thank you,
>> Don.
>> Uh Don Williams, Avalanche Journal. Hey
uh Jacob, I was checking curious to see
what your interactions with dolphins
people had been um in the last several
weeks, couple of months. Did you have
any inclination that they were uh
looking hard at you, looking seriously
uh at taking you?
>> Uh hey Don, good to hear. Good to hear
you again.
>> You too, man.
>> Um
>> thanks.
Uh, no. I mean, I've had some excellent
conversations with them and it's kind of
been through the whole process of, you
know, I was fortunate enough to go to
the senior bowl and then fortunate
enough to go to the combine and, you
know, you get to talk to them, you know,
here and there. Um, it's not necessarily
always official and always, um, you
know, very serious. A lot of it can be
just, you know, small talk and so, but
just every single conversation, every
single interaction with them was
fantastic. It it was truly unbelievable.
Um, so to be, you know, picked by
organization like like Miami, um, it's
unbelievable to be able to join join
that team and and everything that they
got going on and especially to join
Jordan down there, um, would be would be
awesome.
>> Allan,
hey, Jacob, welcome to South Florida.
Uh, since I like to ask the hard-hitting
questions and since it was brought up by
Dolphins assistant GM Kyle Smith, I have
to ask you about the mustache. Uh, how
long have you had it? Do you consider it
your trademark and uh is it a big source
of pride for you?
>> Um, yeah, it's uh it started as a joke.
My wife ended up loving it and so, you
know, I got to keep it and um yeah, it
kind of took took the community by storm
this year. it was myself and then a
couple of guys on the team um who who
had it going and you know by the end of
the season we had you know little girls
who were you know three years old or you
know women who were in the 70s and 80s
wearing the dark mustaches for games and
so um I I don't think I can uh you know
abandon it. I think it's a a part of you
know who I am and um kind of just
represents that that toughness of being
a a Texan and so I I appreciate it but
um it's a it's a good talking point too.
It's a It's a good icebreaker and so I
think it helps keeping it around.
>> So you will bring it to South Florida.
>> Say it again.
>> You will bring it to South Florida?
>> I will. Yes, sir.
>> And officially I think you answered, but
you did not have a 30 visit with the
Dolphins. Correct.
>> No, sir.
>> Okay. Thank you, Jacob.
>> Thank you.
>> We have time for two more. We'll go to
Andrea and then finish with Chris.
>> Thank you. Veril
Miami. Jacob, uh, I wanted to ask you
about your parents. We saw their
celebration and we've read your story
and how you had to live in an apartment
with four other people. What does it
mean to them to make you uh give this
step and and make it to the NFL? Thanks.
>> Um uh thank you. It it means a lot. I
think um you know everything they've
done in my entire life. So, I'm the
youngest of five and so, um, you know,
being the the the youngest and them
always wanted to take care of me and be
in my life, they they've put me in
situations, uh, athletically, um, you
know, in school and in every which way
to prepare me for the future and for for
life ahead. And, uh, I can't thank them
enough for everything they've done for
me, all the sacrifices that they made,
and, um, all all the their generosity
and their love that they were showing me
my entire life. And so I'm just
appreciative of them of who they are and
what kind of traits and character
characteristics they instilled in me.
>> Chris,
>> hey Jacob. Chris Perkins again from the
South Florida Suns Sentinel. Uh fellow
Texan here and um used to work at the
Dallas Morning News Fort Worth Star
Telegram. Been to Witchah Falls, spent
time in Leach. How much does that Texas
pride uh fuel you? The small town being
from Leach. Does it give you a chip on
your shoulder? Tell me about how that
influences you and and and your life.
>> Yeah, it definitely does. I think
anybody from Texas will will argue the
same. And so, um yeah, it definitely
helps. A lot of it has to do with kind
of the work that's being done out here,
especially in West Texas. It's uh it's
tough work out there with the conditions
the way that they are. And it's a it's a
tough way of life. And so, um, you know,
if I'm fortunate enough to play this
game and, you know, I get to go to work
and and my work is to play a game for a
living and I I have nothing to complain
about when I know who people out there
who are really, you know, putting in
long hours and long days just to, you
know, put food on the table for their
families. And so, that's something that
stick with me. Um, it'll stick with me
from now until the to the rest of my
life. And so, um, I'm so appreciative
of, you know, the Lord putting me in
that, you know, position to have that
opportunity to to really, uh, you know,
learn about, um, everything that goes
on, all the ins and outs of being from
around there.